I'm really excited especially for this lecture,
我真的很兴奋，特别是这次演讲，
which is a very special lecture
这是一个非常特别的演讲，
on robust and trustworthy deep learning
关于健壮和值得信赖的深度学习，
by one of our sponsors of this amazing course, Themis AI.
由我们这门令人惊叹的课程的赞助商之一 Themis AI 提供。
And as you'll see today,
正如你们今天将看到的，
Themis AI is a startup actually locally based here in Cambridge,
Temeis AI 是一家总部位于 Cambridge 的初创公司，
our mission is to design, advance and deploy the future of AI and trustworthy AI specifically,
我们的使命是设计、推进和部署人工智能和值得信赖的人工智能，
I'm especially excited about today's lecture,
我尤其对今天的演讲感到兴奋，
because I co-founded Themis right here at MIT,
因为我是 Themis 的联合创始人，就在 MIT ，
right here in this very building, in fact,
就在这里，在这座大楼里，
this all stemmed from really the incredible scientific innovation and advances that we created right here,
这一切都源于我们在这里创造的令人难以置信的科学创新和进步，
just a few floors higher than where you're sitting today,
就在比你们今天坐的地方高几层的地方，
and because of our background in really cutting edge scientific innovation stemming from MIT,
由于我们的背景是 MIT 真正的尖端科学创新，
Themis is very rooted deeply in science and like I said, innovation,
Themis 深深植根于科学，就像我说的，创新，
we really aim to advance the future of deep learning and AI
我们的目标是推动深度学习和人工智能的未来，
and much of our technology has already grown from published research,
我们的许多技术已经从发表的研究成果中成长起来，
that we've published at top tier peer review conferences in the AI [venues] around the world
我们在世界各地人工智能[场馆]的顶级同行评议会议上发表的，
and our work has been covered by high profile international media outlets,
我们的工作得到了国际知名媒体的报道，
this scientific innovation, with this scientific innovation,
通过这种科学创新，
Themis, we are tackling some of the biggest challenges in safety critical AI that exists today,
Themis 我们正在应对当今存在的安全关键人工智能中的一些最大挑战，
and really that stems from the fact,
这实际上源于这样一个事实，
that we want to take all of these amazing advances that you're learning as part of this course
我们希望将所有这些令人惊叹的进步作为本课程的一部分，
and actually achieve them in reality as part of our daily lives
并在现实中作为我们日常生活的一部分来实现，
and we're working together with leading global industry partners across many different disciplines
我们正在与许多不同学科的全球领先行业合作伙伴合作，
ranging from robotics, autonomy health care and more
从机器人学、自主性医疗保健等等，
to develop a line of products,
开发一系列产品，
that will guarantee safe and trustworthy AI
以确保安全和值得信赖的人工智能，
and we drive this really deeply with our technical engineering and machine learning team,
我们的技术工程和机器学习团队一起深入推动这一点，
and our focus is very much on the engineering,
我们的重点是工程，
very flexible and very modular platforms
非常灵活和非常模块化的平台，
to scale algorithms towards robust and trustworthy AI,
将算法扩展到健壮和值得信赖的人工智能，
this really enables this deployment towards grand challenges that our society faces with AI today,
这使这种部署能够应对我们社会今天面临的重大挑战，
specifically the ability for AI solutions today are not very trustworthy at all,
特别是，今天的人工智能解决方案的能力根本不太值得信任，
even if they may be very high performance on some of the tasks that we study as part of this course.
即使它们在我们作为本课程一部分学习的一些任务中可能表现得非常高。
So it's an incredibly exciting time for Themis
所以，对于 Themis 来说，这是一个令人难以置信的令人兴奋的时刻，
and specific right now, where VC backed,
特别是现在风险投资，
we're located our offices are right here in Cambridge, so we're local
我们的办公室就在 Cambridge ，所以我们是本地的，
and we have just closed around the funding,
我们刚刚完成了融资，
so we're actively hiring the best and the brightest engineers, like all of you
所以我们正在积极招聘最优秀、最聪明的工程师，像你们所有人一样，
to realize the future of safe and trustworthy AI
实现安全可靠的人工智能的未来，
and we hope that really today's lecture inspires you
我们希望今天的演讲激励你，
to join us on this mission to build the future of AI.
加入我们的使命，建设人工智能的未来。
And with that it's my great pleasure to introduce Sadhana,
说到这里，我非常高兴地介绍一下 Sadhana ，
Sadhana is a machine learning scientist at Themis,
Sadhana 是 Themis 的一位机器学习科学家，
she's also the lead TA of this course,
她也是这门课程的首席助教，
intro to deep learning at MIT,
MIT 的深度学习入门，
her research at Themis focuses specifically on,
她在 Themis 的研究专注于，
how we can build very modular and flexible methods for AI
我们如何为人工智能构建非常模块化和灵活的方法，
and building what we call a safe and trustworthy AI.
并构建我们所说的安全可靠的人工智能。
And today she'll be teaching us
今天，她将教我们，
more about specifically the bias and the uncertainty realms of AI algorithms,
更多关于人工智能算法的偏见和不确定性领域，
which are really two key or critical components
这是两个关键或关键组件，
towards achieving this mission or this vision of safe and trustworthy deployment of AI all around us.
实现安全可靠地部署我们周围人工智能的使命或愿景。
So thank you and please give a big, warm round of applause for Sadhana.
所以谢谢你们，请给 Sadhana 热烈的掌声。
Thank you so much, Alexander, for the introduction.
Alexander ，非常感谢你的介绍。
Hi everyone. I'm Sadhana,
大家好。我是 Sadhana ，
I'm a machine learning scientist here at Themis AI
我是 Themis AI 的一名机器学习科学家，
and the lead TA of the course this year,
也是今年这门课程的首席助教，
and today I'm super excited to talk to you all about robust and trustworthy deep learning on behalf of Themis.
今天，我非常兴奋地代表 Themis 向你们所有人谈论健壮和值得信赖的深度学习。
So over the past decade,
在过去的十年里，
we've seen some tremendous growth in artificial intelligence, across safety critical domains,
我们看到人工智能在安全关键领域取得了巨大的增长，
in the spheres of autonomy and robotics,
在自主和机器人领域，
we now have models that can make critical decisions about things like self driving at a second's notice,
我们现在的模型可以在一秒钟的时间内对自动驾驶等事情做出关键决定，
and these are paving the way for fully autonomous vehicles and robots,
这些模型为全自动车辆和机器人铺平道路，
and that's not where this stops,
而这并没有停止，
in the spheres of medicine and healthcare,
在医药和医疗保健领域，
robots are now equipped to conduct life saving surgery,
机器人现在已经装备好，可以进行救命手术，
we have algorithms that generate predictions for critical drugs,
我们有算法来生成对关键药物的预测，
that may cure diseases that we previously thought were incurable,
这些药物可能会治愈我们之前认为无法治愈的疾病，
and we have models that can automatically diagnose diseases,
我们的模型可以自动诊断疾病，
without intervention from any health care professionals at all.
而不需要任何卫生保健专业人员的干预。
These advances are revolutionary,
这些进步是革命性的，
and they have the potential to change life as we know it today.
它们有可能改变我们今天所知的生活。
But there's another question that we need to ask,
但还有一个问题我们需要问，
which is where are these models in real life,
那就是这些模型在现实生活中处于什么位置，
a lot of these technologies were innovated five, ten years ago,
这些技术中的许多都是五年前、十年前创新的，
but you and I don't see them in our daily lives,
但你我在日常生活中并没有看到它们，
so what is, what's the gap here between innovation and deployment.
那么，创新和使用之间的差距是什么。
The reason why you and I can't go by self driving cars or robots don't typically assist in operating rooms is this,
你和我不能乘坐自动驾驶汽车或机器人去手术室的原因是这样的，
these are some headlines about the failures of AI from the last few years alone,
这些是仅在过去几年关于人工智能失败的一些头条新闻，
in addition to these incredible advances,
除了这些令人难以置信的进步，
we've also seen catastrophic failures
我们还看到出现了灾难性的故障，
in every single one of the safety critical domains I just mentioned,
我刚才提到的每一个安全关键领域，
these problems range from crashing autonomous vehicles
这些问题包括自动驾驶汽车的撞车，
to health care algorithms that don't actually work for everyone,
以及并不适用于每个人的医疗保健算法，
even though they're deployed out in the real world,
尽管它们部署在现实世界中，
so everyone can use them.
所以每个人都可以使用它们。
Now, at a first glance,
现在，初看起来，
this seems really demoralizing,
这似乎真的让人士气低落，
if these are all of the things wrong with artificial intelligence,
如果这些都是人工智能的问题所在，
how are we ever going to achieve that vision
我们将如何实现这样的愿景，
of having our AI integrated into the fabric of our daily lives
将我们的人工智能整合到我们的日常生活结构中，
in terms of safety critical deployment,
在安全关键部署方面，
but at Themis, this is exactly the type of problem that we solve,
但在 Themis ，这正是我们解决的问题类型，
we want to bring these advances to the real world,
我们希望将这些进步带到现实世界中，
and the way we do this is by innovating in the spheres of safe and trustworthy artificial intelligence
我们做到这一点的方式是在安全和值得信赖的人工智能领域进行创新，
in order to bring the things that were developed in research labs around the world to customers like you and me.
以便将世界各地研究实验室开发的东西带给像你我这样的客户。
And we do this by, our core ideology is that,
我们这样做，我们的核心意识形态是，
we believe that all of the problems on this slide are underlaid by two key notions,
我们相信这张幻灯片上的所有问题都有两个关键概念作为基础，
the first is bias,
首先是偏差，
bias is what happens when machine learning models do better on some demographics than others,
偏差是指机器学习模型在某些人口统计数据上表现得比其他更好，
this results in things like facial detection systems, not being able to detect certain faces with high accuracy,
这导致面部检测系统，无法高精度检测某些人脸，
Siri not being able to recognize voices with accents,
Siri 无法识别带有口音的语音，
or algorithms that are trained on imbalanced data sets,
或者针对不平衡数据集进行训练的算法，
so what the algorithm believes is a good solution
所以，算法相信的是一个好的解决方案，
doesn't actually work for everyone in the real world.
实际上并不适用于现实世界中的每个人。
And the second notion that underlies a lot of these problems today is unmitigated and uncommunicated uncertainty,
许多此类问题背后的第二个概念是无法缓解和无法传达的不确定性，
this is when models don't know when they can or can't be trusted,
这就是模型不知道什么时候可以信任或者不可以信任，
and this results in scenarios,
这导致了一些场景，
such as self driving cars continuing to operate in environments when they're not 100% confident
比如自动驾驶汽车在没有 100% 自信的情况下继续在环境中操作，
instead of giving control to users,
而不是将控制权交给用户，
or robots being moving around in environments that they've never been in before and have high unfamiliarity with.
或者机器人在它们以前从未进入过的环境中移动，并且高度不熟悉。
And a lot of the problems in modern day AI are the result of a combination of unmitigated bias and uncertainty.
现代人工智能中的许多问题都是彻头彻尾的偏差和不确定性的组合的结果。
So today in this lecture,
所以今天在这节课中，
we're going to focus on investigating the root causes of all of these problems,
我们将重点研究所有这些问题的根本原因，
these two big challenges to robust deep learning.
这是健壮深度学习面临的两大挑战。
We'll also talk about solutions for them,
我们还将讨论它们的解决方案，
that can improve the robustness and safety of all of these algorithms for everyone.
可以为每个人提高所有这些算法的健壮性和安全性。
And we'll start by talking about bias.
我们将从讨论偏差开始。
Bias is a word that we've all heard, outside the context of deep learning,
在深度学习的背景下，我们都听说过 Bias 这个词，
but in the context of machine learning, it can be quantified and mathematically defined.
但在机器学习的背景下，它是可以量化和数学定义的。
Today we'll talk about how to do this
今天，我们将讨论如何做到这一点，
and methods for mitigation of this bias algorithmically
从算法上缓解这种偏差的方法，
and how Themis is innovating in these areas
以及 Themis 如何在这些领域进行创新，
in order to bring new algorithms in this space to industries around the world.
以便将该领域的新算法带到世界各地的行业。
Afterwards, we'll talk about uncertainty,
然后，我们将讨论不确定性，
which is, can we teach a model when it does or doesn't know the answer to to its given task,
也就是，我们能教一个模型知道或不知道给定任务的答案吗，
and we'll talk about the ramifications for this for real world AI.
我们将讨论这对现实世界人工智能的影响。
So what exactly does bias mean,
那么，偏差到底是什么意思，
and where is it present in the artificial intelligence lifecycle,
它在人工智能生命周期中处于什么位置，
the most intuitive form of bias comes from data.
最直观的偏差形式来自数据。
We have two different two main types of bias here,
我们这里有两种不同的主要类型的偏差，
the first is sampling bias,
第一种是抽样偏差，
which is when we over sample from some regions of our input data distribution
即从我们的输入数据分布的某些地区过度抽样，
and under sample from others,
而从其他地区抽样不足，
a good example of this is a lot of clinical data sets,
一个很好的例子是大量的临床数据集，
where they often contain fewer examples of diseased patients than healthy patients,
其中包含的疾病患者的例子往往比健康患者少，
because it's much easier to acquire data for healthy patients than their disease counterparts.
因为获得健康患者的数据比获得疾病患者的数据容易得多。
In addition, we also have selection bias at the data portion of the AI life cycle,
此外，在人工智能生命周期的数据部分，我们也存在选择偏差，
think about Apple's series voice recognition algorithm,
想想苹果的一系列语音识别算法，
this model is trained largely on flawless American English,
这个模型主要是根据完美的美式英语训练的，
but it's deployed across the real world
但它被部署在现实世界中，
to be able to recognize voices with accents from all over the world,
以便能够识别来自世界各地的带有口音的声音，
the distribution of the model's training data doesn't match the distribution of this type of language in the real world,
模型的训练数据的分布与现实世界中这类语言的分布不匹配，
because American English is highly overrepresented, as opposed to other demographics.
因为美国英语被严重高估了，与其他人口统计数据相反，
But that's not where, that's not where bias and data stops,
但这并不是问题所在，偏差和数据也不会止步于此，
these biases can be propagated towards models training cycles themselves,
这些偏差可以传播到模型训练循环本身，
which is what we'll focus on in the second half of this lecture.
这是我们在本课程的后半部分将重点关注的。
And then once the model is actually deployed,
然后，一旦模型被实际部署，
which means it's actually put out into the real world
这意味着它被放到了现实世界中，
and customers or users can actually get the predictions from it,
客户或用户可以从它获得预测，
we may see further biases perpetuated that we haven't seen before,
我们可能会看到更多我们以前从未见过的偏差，
the first of these is distribution shifts,
第一个是分布的转变，
let's say I have a model,
假设我有一个模型，
that I trained on the past twenty years of data,
是我根据过去 20 年的数据训练的，
and then I deploy it into the real world,
然后我把它部署到现实世界中，
in 2023, This model will probably do fine,
在 2023 ，这个模型可能会做得很好，
because the data input distribution is quite similar to data in the training distribution,
因为数据输入分布与训练分布中的数据非常相似，
but what would happen to this model in 2033,
但这种模式在 2033 年会发生什么，
it probably would not work as well,
如果它可能不会很好地发挥作用，
because the distribution that the data is coming from would shift significantly across this decade,
因为数据来自的分布将在这十年内发生显着变化，
and if we don't continue to update our models with this input stream of data,
如果我们不继续用这些输入数据流更新我们的模型，
we're going to have obsolete and incorrect predictions.
我们就会得到过时和不正确的预测。
And finally, after deployment, there the evaluation aspect,
最后，部署之后，在评估方面，
so think back to the Apple Siri example that we've been talking about,
回想一下我们谈论的 Apple Siri 的例子，
if the evaluation metric or the evaluation data set that Siri was evaluated on
如果评估 Siri 的评估指标或评估数据集
was also mostly comprised of American English,
也主要由美国英语组成，
then to anybody this model will look like it does extremely well, right,
那么在任何人看来，这个模型都会表现得非常好，
it can detect, it can recognize American English voices with extremely high accuracy
它可以检测，它可以非常高的准确率识别美国英语的声音，
and therefore is deployed into the real world,
此部署到现实世界中，
but what about its accuracy on subgroups,
但它在子组准确率会怎么样，
on accented voices, on people who for whom English is not their first language,
对于带口音的人，那些英语不是他们的第一语言的人，
if we don't also test on subgroups in our evaluation metrics,
如果我们不在我们的评估指标中对子组进行测试，
we're going to face evaluation bias.
我们将面临偏差。
So now let's talk about another example in the real world
现在，让我们来谈谈现实世界中的另一个例子，
of how bias can perpetuate throughout the course of this artificial intelligence life cycle,
关于偏差如何在人工智能生命周期的整个过程中持续存在，
commercial facial detection systems are everywhere,
商用面部检测系统无处不在，
you actually played around with some of them in lab two,
在第二个实验中，你玩了其中一些，
when you trained your VAE on a facial detection data set.
当你在面部检测数据集上训练你的 VAE 时。
In addition to the lock screens on your cell phones,
除了手机上的锁屏外，
facial detection systems are also present in the automatic filters,
面部检测系统还安装在自动滤镜中，
that your phone cameras apply,
你的手机摄像头就会应用这些，
whenever you try to take a picture,
每当你拍照时，
and they're also used in criminal investigations.
它们也被用于刑事调查。
These are three commercial facial detection systems that were deployed,
这是三个部署的商用面部检测系统，
and we'll analyze the biases that might have been present in all of them for in the next few minutes.
我们将在接下来的几分钟内分析所有系统中可能存在的偏差。
So the first thing you may notice is that,
所以，你可能会注意到的第一件事是，
there is a huge accuracy gap between two different demographics in this plot,
在这张图中，两个不同的人口统计数据之间存在巨大的准确性差距，
this accuracy gap can get up to 34%,
这个精度差距最高可达 34% ，
keep in mind, that this facial detection is a binary classification task,
请记住，这个面部检测是一个二进制分类任务，
everything is either a face or it's not a face,
每件事要么是脸，要么不是脸，
this means that a randomly initialized model would be expected to have an accuracy of 50%,
这意味着随机初始化的模型应该有 50% 的准确率，
because it's going to randomly assign whether or not something is a face or not,
因为它将随机指定某个东西是否是人脸，
some of these facial detection classifiers do only barely better than random
其中一些面部检测分类器表现仅略好于随机，
on these underrepresented data, on these underrepresented samples in this population.
对这个群体这些代表性不足的数据，这些代表性不足的样本上。
So how did this happen,
那么这是怎么发生的，
why is there such a blatant gap in accuracy between these different demographic groups,
为什么这些不同的人口群体在准确性方面存在如此明显的差距，
and how did these models ever get deployed in the first place,
这些模型最初是如何部署的，
what types of biases were present in these models.
这些模型中存在哪些类型的偏差。
So a lot of facial detection systems exhibit very clear selection bias,
许多人脸检测系统表现出非常明显的选择偏见，
this model was likely trained mostly on lighter skin faces
这个模型很可能主要是针对浅色皮肤的面孔进行训练，
and therefore learned those much more effectively than it learned to classify darker skin faces.
因此学习这些面孔比学习对深色皮肤的面孔进行分类要有效得多。
But that's not the only bias that was present,
但这并不是唯一存在的偏差，
the second bias that's often very present in facial detection systems is evaluation bias,
面部检测系统中经常出现的第二个偏差是评估偏差，
because originally this data set that you see on the screen
因为最初你在屏幕上看到的这个数据集，
is not the data set that these models were evaluated on,
并不是评估这些模型所依据的数据集，
they were evaluated on one big bulk data set,
它们是在一个大数据集上进行评估的，
without any classification into subgroups at all,
根本没有对子组进行任何分类，
and therefore you can imagine,
因此，你可以想象，
if the dataset was also comprised mostly of lighter skinned faces,
如果数据集也主要由白皮肤的人脸组成，
these accuracy metrics would be incredibly inflated
这些精确度指标将被难以置信地夸大，
and therefore would cause unnecessary confidence
因此会产生不必要的信心，
and we could deploy them into the real world.
我们可以将它们部署到现实世界中。
In fact, the biases in these models were only uncovered,
事实上，这些模型中的偏差被发现，
once an independent study actually constructed a data set,
只有当一项独立研究真正构建了一个数据集，
that is specifically designed to uncover these sorts of biases,
专门用于揭示这些类型的偏差，
by balancing across race and gender.
通过平衡种族和性别。
However, there are other ways that data sets can be biased,
然而，数据集可能存在偏见的其他方面，
that we haven't yet talked about.
我们还没有讨论过。
So, so far we've assumed a pretty key assumption in our data set,
到目前为止，我们已经在我们的数据集中假设了一个非常关键的假设，
which is that the number of faces in our data is the exact same as the number of non faces in our data,
那就是我们数据中的人脸数量与数据中的非人脸数量完全相同，
but you can imagine,
但你可以想象，
especially if you're looking at things like security feeds,
特别是如果你在查看安全提要之类的东西，
this might not always be the case,
情况可能并不总是如此，
you might be faced with many more negative samples than positive samples in your data set.
在你的数据集中，你可能会面临比正样本多得多的负样本。
In the most,
在最的情况下，
so what's the problem here,
那么这里有什么问题，
in the most extreme case,
在最极端的情况下，
we may assign the label non-face to every item in the data set,
我们可能会为数据集中的每个项目分配标签 non-face ，
because the model sees items that are labeled as faces,
因为模型很少看到被标记为 face 的项目，
so infrequently that it isn't able to learn,
以至于它无法学习，
an accurate class boundary between the two sample, between the two classes.
两个分类之间，两个样本之间的准确分类边界。
So how can we mitigate this,
那么，我们如何才能缓解这种情况，
this is a really big problem
这是一个非常大的问题，
and it's very common across a lot of different types of machine learning tasks and data sets.
在许多不同类型的机器学习任务和数据集中都很常见。
And the first way that we can try to mitigate class imbalance is using sample re-weighting,
我们可以尝试缓解类别失衡的第一种方法是使用样本重新加权，
which is when instead of uniformly sampling from our data set at a rate,
即不是以速率从我们的数据集中统一采样，
we instead sample at a rate that is inversely proportional to the incidence of a class in our data set,
而是以与我们数据集中某个类别的发生率成反比的速率进行采样，
so in the previous example,
因此，在前面的例子中，
if the likelihood if faces were much,
如果人脸的可能性很小，
if the number of faces was much lower than the number of non faces in our data set,
如果人脸的数量比我们数据集中的非人脸的数量少得多，
we would sample the faces with a higher probability than the negatives,
我们将以比[负]更高的概率对人脸进行采样，
so that the model sees both classes equally.
这样模型就可以平等地看到这两种类别。
The second example, the second way we can mitigate class imbalance is through loss re-rating,
第二个例子，我们可以缓解类别失衡的第二种方法是通过损失重新评级，
which is when instead of having every single mistake that the model makes contribute equally to our total loss function,
即不是让模型中的每个错误对总损失函数做出相等的贡献，
we're weight the samples,
我们对样本进行加权，
such that samples from underrepresented classes contribute more to the loss function,
比如来自未被充分代表的类别的样本对损失函数有更大的贡献，
so instead of the model assigning every single input face to a as a negative,
因此，与模型将每个单一输入面分配为负数不同，
it'll be highly penalized, if it does so,
如果它这样做，它将受到极大的惩罚，
because the loss of the faces would contribute more to the total loss function than the loss of the negatives.
因为面数的损失将比负损失对总损失函数的贡献更大。
And the final way that we can mitigate class imbalance is through batch selection,
我们可以缓解分类不平衡的最后一种方法是通过批量选择，
which is when we choose randomly from classes,
这是当我们从类中随机选择时，
so that every single batch has an equal number of data points per class.
这样每一批都有每个类相同数量的数据点。
So is everything solved,
那么一切都解决了吗，
clearly, there are other forms of bias that exist,
显然，也存在其他形式的偏差，
even when the classes are completely balanced,
即使分类完全平衡，
because the thing that we haven't thought about yet is latent features.
因为我们还没有考虑到的是潜在特征。
So if you remember from lab two and the last lecture,
如果你们还记得实验二和上一节课的内容，
latent features are the actual represent, is the actual representation of this image according to the model.
潜在特征实际代表，通过模型实际代表这个图像。
And so far we've mitigated the problem of when we know that we have underrepresented classes,
到目前为止，我们已经缓解了当我们知道我们有代表不足的类时的问题，
but we haven't mitigated the problem of when we have a lot of variability within the same class.
但我们还没有减轻当我们在同一个类中有大量可变性的问题。
Let's say we have an equal number of faces and negative examples in our data set,
让我们假设我们的数据集中有相同数量的人脸和反面例子，
what happens if the majority of the faces are from a certain demographic
如果大多数人脸来自特定的人群，
or they have a certain set of features,
或者他们有一套特定的特征，会发生什么，
can we still apply the techniques that we just learned about,
我们还能应用我们刚刚学到的技术，
the answer is that we cannot do this,
答案是我们不能这样做，
and the problem is that the bias present right now is in our latent features.
问题是目前存在的偏差存在于我们的潜在特征中。
All of these images are labeled with the exact same label,
所有这些图像都被贴上了完全相同的标签，
so according to as the model, all we know is that they're all faces,
所以根据模型，我们所知道的就是它们都是人脸，
so we have no information about any of these features, only from the label,
因此，我们没有关于这些功能的任何信息，只有标签上的信息，
therefore we can't apply any of the previous approaches that we used to mitigate class imbalanced,
因此，我们不能应用以前用来缓解分类不平衡的任何方法，
because our classes are balanced,
因为我们的分类是平衡的，
but we have feature imbalance now.
但我们现在有特征不平衡。
However, we can adapt the previous methods to account for bias in latent features,
然而，我们可以调整前面的方法来解释潜在特征中的偏差，
which we'll do in just a few slides.
这将在几张幻灯片中完成。
So let's unpack this a little bit further,
所以让我们进一步了解一下这个问题，
we have our potentially biased data set,
我们有可能有偏差的数据集，
and we're trying to build and deploy a model,
我们试图建立和部署一个模型，
that classifies the faces in a traditional training pipeline,
在传统的训练管道中对人脸进行分类，
this is what that pipeline would look like,
这就是那条管道的样子，
We would train our classifier
我们将训练我们的分类器，
and we would deploy it into the real world,
并将其部署到现实世界中，
but this training pipeline doesn't debias our inputs in any way.
但这种训练管道丝毫不会 debias 我们的输入。
So one thing we could do is label our biased features and then apply resampling.
.因此，我们可以做的一件事是标记我们的偏差特征，然后应用重新采样。
So, let's say in reality,
因此，让我们假设在现实中，
that this data set was biased on hair color,
这个数据集是对头发颜色的偏见，
most of the data set is made up of people with blonde hair,
大多数数据集由金发的人组成，
with faces with black hair and red hair underrepresented,
黑发和红发的脸没有得到充分的代表，
if we knew this information,
如果我们知道这个信息，
we could label the hair color of every single person in this data set,
我们就可以标记这个数据集中每个人的头发颜色，
and we could apply either sample weighting or loss re-weighting,
我们可以应用样本加权或损失重新加权，
just as we did previously.
就像我们之前所做的那样。
But does anyone want to tell me what the problem is here?
但有没有人想告诉我问题出在哪里？
You go through each samples, it takes a lot of time.
你要检查每个样本，要花很多时间。
Yeah, so there are a couple problems here,
是的，所以这里有几个问题，
and that's definitely one of them.
这绝对是其中之一。
The first is,
第一个问题是，
how do we know that hair color is a biased feature in this data set,
我们如何知道头发颜色在这个数据集中是一个有偏见的特征，
unless we visually inspect every single sample in this data set,
除非我们肉眼检查这个数据集中的每一个样本，
we're not going to know what the biased features are.
否则我们不会知道哪些是有偏差的特征。
And the second thing is exactly what you said,
第二件事正是你所说的，
which is once we have our biased features,
那就是一旦我们有了我们有偏差的特征，
going through and annotating every image with this feature is an extremely labor intensive task,
浏览和注释每一张带有这个特征的图像是一项极其劳动密集型的任务，
that is infeasible in the real world.
在现实世界中是不可行的。
So now the question is,
所以现在的问题是，
what if we had a way to automatically learn latent features
如果我们有一种方法来自动学习潜在特征，
and use this learn feature representation to debias a model.
并使用这种学习特征表示法来描述一个模型。
So what we want is a way to learn the features of this data set
因此，我们想要的是一种方法来学习这个数据集的特征，
and then automatically determine the samples with the highest feature bias and the samples with the lowest feature bias,
然后自动确定具有最高特征偏差的样本和具有最低特征偏差的样本，
we've already learned a method of doing this,
我们已经学习了这样做的方法，
in the generative modeling lecture, you all learned about variational autoencoders,
在生成建模课程中，你们都学过变分自编码器，
which are models that learn the latent features of a data set,
这是一种从数据集种学习潜在特征的模型，
as a recap, variational autoencoders work by probabilistically sampling from a learn latent space,
回顾一下，变分自编码器从学习的潜在空间进行概率采样，
and then they decode this new latent vector into back into the original input space,
然后它们将这个新的潜在向量解码到原始输入空间，
measure the reconstruction loss between the inputs and the outputs,
测量输入和输出之间的重建损失，
and continue to update their representation of the latent space.
并继续更新它们对潜在空间的表示。
And the reason why we care so much about this latent space
我们之所以如此关心这个潜在空间，
is that we want samples that are similar to each other in the input
是因为我们希望输入中彼此相似的样本
to decode to latent vectors that are very close to each other in this latent space,
解码成在这个潜在空间中彼此非常接近的潜在向量，
and samples that are far from each other or samples that are dissimilar to each other in the input
而输入中相距较远的样本或不相似的样本
should decode encode to latent vectors that are far from each other in the latent space.
应解码编码为在潜在空间中彼此相距较远的潜在向量。
So now we'll walk through step by step a debiasing algorithm,
所以，现在我们将逐步介绍一种 debias 算法，
that automatically uses the latent features learned by a variational autoencoder,
该算法自动通过变分自编码器使用潜在特征学习，
to under sample and over sample from regions in our data set.
对数据集中的区域进行欠采样和过采样。
Before I start,
在我开始之前，
I want to point out that this debiasing model is actually the foundation of Themis's work,
我想指出这个 debias 模型实际上是 Themis 工作的基础，
this work comes out of a paper that we published a few years ago,
这项工作来自我们几年前发表的一篇论文，
that has been demonstrated to debias commercial facial detection algorithms,
演示了 debias 商业面部检测算法，
and it was so impactful,
它的影响力如此之大，
that we decided to make it available and work with companies and industries,
以至于我们决定提供它，并与公司和行业合作，
and that's how Themis was started.
Themis 就是这样开始的。
So let's first start by training a VAE on this data set,
所以，让我们首先对 VAE 进行关于这个数据集的训练，
the z shown here in this diagram ends up being our latent space,
这张图中显示的 z 最终是我们的潜在空间，
and the latent space automatically captures features that were important for classification.
并且潜在空间自动捕获对分类重要的特征。
So here's an example, latent feature that this model captured,
这是一个例子，这个模型捕捉到的潜在特征，
this is the facial position of an input face,
这是输入人脸的面部位置，
and something that's really crucial here is that,
这里真正关键的一点是，
we never told the model
我们从来没有告诉模型，
to calculate, to encode the feature vector of the facial position of a given face,
计算，编码给定人脸面部位置的特征向量，
it learned this automatically,
它会自动学习这一点，
because this feature is important for the model
因为这一特征对于模型很重要，
to develop a good representation of what a face actually is.
对于开发出一个很好的人脸是什么样子的表示。
So now that we have our latent structure,
现在我们有了我们的潜在结构，
we can use it to calculate a distribution of the inputs across every latent variable,
我们可以用它来计算输入在每个潜在变量上的分布，
and we can estimate a probability distribution
我们可以估计概率分布，
depending on that's based on the features of every item in this data set,
根据这个数据集中每一项的特征，
essentially, what this means is that,
本质上，这意味着，
we can calculate the probability that a certain combination of features appears in our data set
我们可以计算特定特征组合出现在我们的数据集中的概率，
based on the latent space that we just learned,
基于我们刚刚学习的潜在空间。
and then we can over sample denser, sparser areas of this data set
然后我们可以对该数据集较稀疏的区域进行过采样，
and under sample from denser areas of this data set.
并从该数据集的较密集区域进行欠采样。
So let's say our distribution looks something like this,
假设我们的分布是这样的，
this is an oversimplification,
这是过于简单化了，
but for visualization purposes
但为了可视化的目的，
and the denser portions of this data set,
这个数据集的更密集的部分，
we would expect to have a homogeneous skin color and pose in hair color and very good lighting,
我们希望有一个均匀的肤色和头发颜色的姿势，以及非常好的照明，
and then in the sparser portions of this data set,
然后在这个数据集的较稀疏部分，
we would expect to see diverse skin color, pose and illumination,
我们预计会看到不同的肤色、姿势和照明，
so now that we have this distribution
现在我们有了这个分布，
and we know what areas of our distribution are dense and which areas are sparse,
我们知道了我们分布的哪些区域是密集的，哪些区域是稀疏的，
we want to under sample areas from the, under sample samples that fall in the denser areas of this distribution
我们想要从落在这个分布的密集区域中的欠采样，
and over sample data points that fall in the sparser areas of this distribution.
在这个分布的稀疏区域中的过采样数据点。
So for example,
例如，
we would probably under sample points with the very common skin colors, hair colors and good lighting,
我们可能会对普通的肤色、发色和良好光照的欠采样，
that is extremely present in this data set
在这个数据集中非常常见，
and over sample the diverse images that we saw on the last slide,
对我们在上一张幻灯片中看到的各种图像进行过采样，
and this allows us to train in a fair and unbiased manner.
这允许我们以公平和不偏不倚的方式进行训练。
To dig in a little bit more into the math behind how this resampling works,
为了更深入地了解重采样背后的数学原理，
this approach basically approximates the latent space via a joint histogram over the individual latent variables,
这种方法基本上是通过对单个潜在变量的联合直方图来近似潜在空间，
so we have a histogram for every latent variable zi,
所以我们对每个潜在变量 zi 都有一个直方图，
and what the histogram essentially does is
这个直方图主要做的是，
it discretizes the continuous distribution,
它离散化连续分布，
so that we can calculate probabilities more easily.
这样我们就可以更容易地计算概率。
Then we multiply the probabilities together across all of the latent distributions,
然后我们将所有潜在分布的概率相乘，
and then after that we can develop an understanding of the joint distribution of all of the samples in our latent space.
然后我们可以了解所有样本在潜在空间中的联合分布。
Based on this,
在此基础上，
we can define the adjusted probability for sampling for a particular data point as follows,
我们可以定义特定数据点的调整后的抽样概率如下，
the probability of selecting a sample data point x will be based on the latent space of x,
选择样本数据点 x 的概率将基于 x 的潜在空间，
such that it is the inverse of the joint approximated distribution,
从而它是联合近似分布的逆，
we have a parameter α here,
我们这里有一个参数 α ，
which is a biasing parameter,
这是一个偏置参数，
and as α increases,
随着 α 的增加，
this probability will tend to the uniform distribution,
这个概率将趋于均匀分布，
and if α increases, we tend to de bias more strongly.
如果 α 增加，我们倾向于更强烈地去偏置。
And this gives us the final weight of the sample in our data set,
这给了我们数据集中样本的最终权重，
that we can calculate on the fly
我们可以动态计算，
and use it to adaptively resample while training.
并在训练时使用它来自适应地重新采样。
And so once we apply this biasing,
因此，一旦我们应用了这种偏差，
we have pretty remarkable results,
我们就会有非常显著的结果，
this is the original graph,
这是原始的图，
that shows the accuracy gap between the darker Males and the lighter Males in this dataset.
显示了此数据集中深色男性和浅色男性之间的精度差距。
Once we apply the debias algorithm,
一旦我们应用了 debias 算法，
where as α gets smaller,
随着 α 变得越来越小，
we're debiasing more and more,
我们 debias 的越来越多，
as we just talked about,
正如我们刚才所说的，
this accuracy gap decreases significantly
这种精度差距显著减小，
and that's because we tend to over sample samples with darker skin color
这是因为我们倾向于对肤色较深的样本进行采样，
and therefore the model learns them better
因此模型会更好地学习它们，
and tends to do better on them.
并倾向于在它们身上做得更好。
Keep this algorithm in mind,
记住这个算法，
because you're going to need it for the lab 3 competition,
因为你们在实验 3 的比赛中会用到它，
which I'll talk more about towards the end of this lecture.
我会在这节课的最后更多地讲到。
So, so far we've been focusing mainly on facial recognition systems and a couple of other systems
到目前为止，我们主要关注面部识别系统和其他几个系统，
as canonical examples of bias.
作为偏见的典型例子。
However, bias is actually far more widespread in machine learning,
然而，在机器学习中，偏见实际上要普遍得多，
consider the example of autonomous driving,
以自动驾驶为例，
many data sets are comprised mainly of cars driving down straight and sunny roads
许多数据集主要包括行驶在阳光明媚的笔直道路上的汽车，
in really good weather conditions with very high visibility,
在非常好的天气条件下，能见度非常高，
and this is because the data for these cars for these algorithms
这是因为这些算法中这些汽车的数据
is actually just collected by cars driving down roads,
是由行驶在道路上的汽车收集的，
however, in some specific cases,
然而，在一些特定的情况下，
you're going to face adverse weather, bad, bad visibility, near collision scenarios,
你将面临恶劣的天气，糟糕的能见度，接近碰撞的场景，
and these are actually the samples that are the most important for the model to learn,
这些样本实际上是模型需要学习的最重要的样本，
because they're the hardest samples
因为它们是最难的样本，
and they're the samples where the model is most likely to fail.
也是模型最有可能失败的样本。
But in a traditional autonomous driving pipeline,
但在传统的自动驾驶管道中，
these samples are often extremely low, have extremely low representation,
这些样本往往极低，代表性极低，
so this is an example where using the unsupervised latent biasing that we just talked about,
因此，这是一个例子，使用我们刚才谈到的无监督潜在偏差，
we would be able to up sample these important data points
我们将能够对这些重要数据点进行过采样，
and under sample the data points of driving down straight and sunny roads.
并对沿着笔直和阳光明媚的道路行驶的数据点进行欠采样。
Similarly, consider the example of large language models,
同样，考虑一下大型语言模型的例子，
an extremely famous paper a couple years ago showed that,
几年前，一篇非常著名的论文表明，
if you put terms that imply female or woman into a large language model powered job search engine,
如果你在一个大型语言模型支持的求职搜索引擎中输入暗示女性或女性的条目，
you're going to get roles such as artist or things in the humanities,
你将获得艺术家等人文学科的角色，
but if you input similar things, but of the male counterpart,
但如果你输入类似的东西，但是男性的，
you put things like male into the the search engine,
你把男性之类的东西放进搜索引擎，
you'll end up with roles for scientists and engineers,
你最终会得到科学家和工程师的角色，
so this type of bias also occurs,
所以这种类型的偏见也会发生，
regardless of the task at hand for a specific model.
而不管特定模型的手头任务是什么。
And finally, let's talk about health care recommendation algorithms,
最后，让我们来谈谈医疗保健推荐算法，
these recommendation algorithms tend to amplify racial biases,
这些推荐算法往往会放大种族偏见，
a paper from a couple years ago showed that,
几年前的一篇论文显示，
black patients need to be significantly sicker than their white counterparts
黑人患者的病情需要比白人患者严重得多，
to get the same level of care,
才能得到同样水平的护理，
and that's because of inherent bias in the data set of this model.
这是因为这个模型的数据集存在固有的偏见。
And so in all of these examples,
因此，在所有这些例子中，
we can use the above algorithmic bias mitigation method
我们可以使用上面的算法偏差缓解方法
to try and solve these problems and more.
来尝试解决这些问题和更多问题。
So we just went through how to mitigate some forms of bias in artificial intelligence
因此，我们讨论了如何减轻人工智能中的某些形式的偏差，
and where these solutions may be applied,
以及这些解决方案可能适用于哪里，
and we talked about a foundational algorithm that Themis uses,
我们谈到了 Themis 使用的一种基本算法，
that you all will also be developing today.
你们今天也将开发它。
And for the next part of the lecture,
在课程的下一部分，
we'll focus on uncertainty
我们将关注不确定性，
or when a model does not know the answer,
或者模型不知道答案的时候，
we'll talk about why uncertainty is important
我们将讨论为什么不确定性很重要，
and how we can estimate it,
我们如何估计它，
and also the applications of uncertainty estimation.
以及不确定性估计的应用。
So, to start with, what is uncertainty
那么，首先，什么是不确定性，
and why is it necessary to compute.
为什么需要计算。
Let's look at the following example,
让我们看一下下面的例子，
this is a binary classifier that is trained on images of cats and dogs,
这是一个对猫和狗的图像进行训练的二进制分类器，
for every single input,
对于每一个输入，
it will output a probability distribution over these two classes.
它将输出这两个类的概率分布。
Now, let's say I give this model an image of a horse,
现在，让我们假设我给这个模型一个马的图像，
it's never seen a horse before,
它以前从来没有见过马，
the horse is clearly neither a cat nor a dog,
这匹马显然既不是猫也不是狗，
however the model has no choice, but to output a probability distribution,
然而，该模型别无选择，只能输出概率分布，
because that's how this model is structured.
因为这就是该模型的结构。
However, what if in addition to this prediction,
然而，如果除了这个预测之外，
we also achieved a confidence estimate,
我们还实现了一个置信度估计，
in this case, the model which should be able to say,
在这种情况下，模型应该能够说，
I've never seen anything like this before
我以前从未见过这样的事情，
and I have very low confidence in this prediction,
我对这个预测的信心很低，
so you as the user should not trust my prediction on this model,
所以，作为用户，你不应该相信我对这个模型的预测，
and that's the core idea behind uncertainty estimation.
这是不确定性估计背后的核心思想。
So in the real world,
因此，在现实世界中，
uncertainty estimation is useful for scenarios like this,
不确定性估计对于这样的场景是有用的，
this is an example of a Tesla car driving behind a horse drawn buggy,
这是特斯拉汽车跟在马车后面行驶的一个例子，
which are very common in some parts of the United States,
这在美国一些地区非常常见，
it has no idea what this horse drawn buggy is,
它根本不知道这辆马车是什么，
it first thinks it's a truck and then a car and then a person,
它首先认为它是一辆卡车，然后是一辆汽车，然后是一个人，
and it continues to output predictions,
然后它继续输出预测，
even though it is very clear that the model does not know what this image is.
即使很明显，模型不知道这是什么图像。
And now you might be asking,
现在你可能会问，
okay, so what's the big deal,
好吧，这有什么大不了的，
it didn't recognize the horse drawn buggy,
它没有认出这辆马车，
but it seemed to drive successfully anyway,
但它似乎还是开得很成功，
however, the exact same problem that resulted in that video
然而，导致这段视频的完全相同的问题
has also resulted in numerous autonomous car crashes.
也导致了许多自动驾驶汽车相撞。
So let's go through why something like this might have happened,
所以让我们来看看为什么会发生这样的事情，
there are multiple different types of uncertainty in neural networks,
神经网络中有多种不同类型的不确定性，
which may cause incidents like the ones that we just saw,
这可能会导致像我们刚刚看到的那样的事件，
we'll go through a simple example that illustrates the two main types of uncertainty,
我们将通过一个简单的例子来说明两种主要类型的不确定性，
that we'll focus on in this lecture.
我们将在这节课中重点讨论。
So let's say I'm trying to estimate the curve y equals x cubed
假设我正在尝试估计曲线 y 等于 x 的立方，
as part of a regression task,
作为回归任务的一部分，
the input here, x is some real number,
这里的输入 x 是一个实数，
and we want it to output f of x,
我们希望它输出 f(x) ，
which should be ideally x cubed.
理想情况下应该是 x 的立方。
So right away you might notice that, there are some issues in this data set,
你可能会立即注意到此数据集中存在一些问题，
assume the red points in this image are your training samples,
假设图像中的红点是你的训练样本，
so the box area of this image shows data points in our data set,
所以这张图的方框区域显示了我们数据集中的数据点，
where we have really high noise,
其中我们有非常高的噪声，
these points do not follow the curve y equals x cubed,
这些点不遵循曲线 y 等于 x 立方，
in fact, they don't really seem to follow any distribution at all,
事实上，它们似乎根本不遵循任何分布，
and the model won't be able to compute outputs for points in this region accurately,
而且该模型将无法准确计算该区域内点的输出，
because very similar inputs have extremely different outputs,
因为非常相似的输入具有非常不同的输出，
which is the definition of data uncertainty.
这是数据不确定性的定义。
We also have regions in this data set, where we have no data,
在这个数据集中，我们还有一些没有数据的地区，
so if we queried the model for a prediction in this part of in this region of the data set,
因此，如果我们在模型中查询这部分数据集的预测，
we should not really expect to see an accurate result,
我们不应该真的期望看到准确的结果，
because the model's never seen anything like this before,
因为模型以前从未见过这样的事情，
and this is what is called model uncertainty,
这就是所谓的模型不确定性，
when the model hasn't seen enough data points
当模型没有看到足够多的数据点，
or cannot estimate that area of the input distribution
或者不能足够准确地估计输入分布的区域
accurately enough to output a correct prediction.
以输出正确的预测时。
So what would happen,
那么会发生什么情况，
if I added the following blue training points
如果我添加以下蓝色训练点，
to the areas of the data set with high model uncertainty,
到模型不确定性较高的数据集区域，
do you think the model uncertainty would decrease,
你认为模型的不确定性会减少吗，
raise your hand.
请举手。
Does anyone think it would not change?
有人认为它不会改变吗？
Okay, so yeah, most of you were correct,
好的，是的，你们大多数人都是对的，
model uncertainty can typically be reduced
模型不确定性通常可以被减少，
by adding in data into any region,
通过将数据添加到任何区域，
but specifically regions with high model uncertainty.
尤其是模型不确定性较高的区域。
And now, what happens if we add these blue data points into this data set,
现在，如果我们将这些蓝色数据点添加到这个数据集中会发生什么，
would anyone expect the data uncertainty to decrease,
有人预计数据的不确定性会降低吗，
raise your hand.
请举手。
That's correct, so data uncertainty is irreducible,
没错，数据不确定性是不可减少的，
in the real world,
在真实的世界中，
the blue points and the noisy red points on this image correspond to things like robot sensors,
这张图像上的蓝点和嘈杂的红点对应于机器人传感器之类的东西，
let's say I I have a robot,
比方说，我有一个机器人，
that's trained to has a sensor that is making measurements of depth,
它被训练成有一个传感器来测量深度，
if the sensor has noise in it,
如果传感器中有噪音，
there's no way that I can add any more data into the system to reduce that noise,
我就无法向系统中添加更多数据来降低噪音，
unless I replace my sensor entirely.
除非我完全更换传感器。
So now let's assign some names to the types of uncertainty that we just talked about,
因此，现在让我们为我们刚刚谈到的不确定性类型指定一些名称，
the blue area or the area of high data uncertainty is known as aleatoric uncertainty,
蓝色区域或数据高度不确定的区域，被称为偶然不确定性，
it is irreducible, as we just mentioned,
它是不可减少的，正如我们刚才提到的，
and it can be directly learned from data,
它可以直接从数据中学习，
which we'll talk about in a little bit.
我们稍后会谈到这一点。
The green areas of, the green boxes that we talked about,
我们所说的绿色盒子，绿色区域，
which were model uncertainty, are known as epistemic uncertainty,
也就是模型的不确定性，被称为认知不确定性，
and this cannot be learned directly from the data,
这不能直接从数据中得知，
however, it can be reduced by adding more data into our systems into these regions.
然而，通过在我们的系统中向这些地区添加更多数据，可以减少这种情况。
Okay, so first let's go through aleatoric uncertainty,
好的，那么首先让我们来看看偶然不确定性，
so the goal of estimating aleatoric uncertainty is
因此，估计偶然不确定性的目标是
to learn a set of variances that correspond to the input,
学习一组与输入相对应的方差，
keep in mind that we are not looking at a data distribution
请记住，我们看到的不是数据分布，
and we are as humans are not estimating the variance,
因为我们人类不会估计差异，
we're training the model to do this task,
我们训练模型来完成这项任务，
and so what that means is typically,
这通常意味着，
when we train a model,
当我们训练一个模型时，
we give it an input x
我们给它一个输入 x ，
and we expect an output ŷ,
我们期望一个输出 ŷ ，
which is the prediction of the model,
这是模型的预测，
now we also predict an additional σ squared,
现在我们还预测了额外的 σ 平方，
so we add another layer to our model,
因此我们在我们的模型中增加了另一层，
we have the same output size
我们有相同的输出大小，
that predicts a variance for every output.
可以预测每个产出的方差。
So the reason why we do this is that,
因此，我们这样做的原因是，
we expect that areas in our data set with high data uncertainty are going to have higher variance,
我们预计数据集中具有高数据不确定性的区域将具有更高的方差，
and the crucial thing to remember here is that,
这里要记住的关键一点是，
this variance is not constant,
这种方差并不是恒定的，
it depends on the value of x,
这取决于 x 的值，
we typically tend to think of variance as a single number,
我们通常倾向于认为方差是一个单独的数字，
that parameterizes an entire distribution,
它将整个分布参数化，
however, in this case,
然而，在这种情况下，
we may have areas of our input distribution with really high variance,
我们的输入分布的区域可能具有非常高的方差，
and we may have areas with very low variance,
而我们可能具有非常低的方差，
so our variance cannot be independent of the input,
所以我们的方差不能独立于输入，
and it depends on our input x.
它取决于我们的输入 x 。
So now that we have this model,
所以现在我们有了这个模型，
we have an extra layer attached to it,
我们有了一个额外的层，
in addition to predicting ŷ, we also predict a σ squared,
除了预测 ŷ ，我们还预测了 σ 平方，
how do we train this model.
我们如何训练这个模型。
Our current loss function does not take into account variance at any point,
我们的当前损失函数不考虑任何点的变化，
this is your typical mean squared error loss function that is used to train regression models,
这是用于训练回归模型的典型均方误差损失函数，
and there's no way training from this loss function,
不可能通过这个损失函数的训练，
that we can learn whether or not the variance that we're estimating is accurate.
我们知道我们估计的方差是否准确。
So in addition to adding another layer to estimate aleatoric uncertainty correctly,
因此，除了增加另一层来估计偶然不确定性外，
we also have to change our loss function.
我们还必须改变我们的损失函数。
So the mean squared error actually learns a multivariate Gaussian
所以均方误差实际上学习的是多元高斯函数，
with a mean yi and constant variance,
它有一个均值 yi ，一个常方差，
and we want to generalize this loss function to when we don't have constant variance,
我们想把这个损失函数推广到，当我们没有常方差时，
and the way we do this is by changing the loss function to the negative log likelihood,
我们做到这一点的方法是将损失函数改为负对数可能性，
we can think about this for now as a generalization of the mean squared error loss to non constant variances,
我们现在可以认为这是均方误差损失到非常数方差的推广，
so now that we have a σ squared term in our loss function,
现在我们在损失函数中有了 σ 平方项，
we can determine how accurately the σ and the y that we're predicting,
我们可以确定我们预测的 σ 和 y 对分布精度，
parameterize the distribution that is our input.
对我们的输入分布进行参数化。
So now that we know how to estimate aleatoric uncertainty,
现在我们知道了如何估计偶然不确定性，
let's look at a real world example,
让我们来看一个真实世界的例子，
for this task, we'll focus on semantic segmentation,
在本任务中，我们将重点介绍语义分割，
which is when we label every pixel of an image with its corresponding class,
也就是用相应的类标记图像的每个像素，
we do this for scene understanding
我们这样做是为了理解场景，
and because it is more fine grained than a typical object detection algorithm.
因为它比典型的目标检测算法更细粒度。
So the inputs of this to this data set are known as it's from a data set called citycapes,
所以这个数据集的输入就是所谓的城市景观数据集，
and the inputs are RGB images of scenes,
它的输入是场景的 RGB 图像，
the labels are pixel wise annotations of this entire image,
标签是整个图像的像素级别注释，
of which label every pixel belongs to,
每个像素都属于它的标签，
and the outputs try to mimic the labels,
并且输出试图模仿标签，
there are also predicted pixel wise masks,
也有预测的像素级别掩码，
so why would we expect that this data set has high natural aleatoric uncertainty,
所以为什么我们会期望这个数据集具有高度的自然偶然不确定性，
and which parts of this data set do you think would have aleatoric uncertainty.
你认为这个数据集的哪些部分会有偶然不确定性。
Because labeling every single pixel of an image is such a labor intensive task,
因为标记图像的每一个像素都是一项劳动密集型的任务，
and it's also very hard to do accurately,
而且很难做到准确，
we would expect that the boundaries between, between objects in this image have high aleatoric uncertainty,
所以我们预计这张图像中对象之间的边界具有高度的偶然不确定性，
and that's exactly what we see,
这正是我们所看到的，
if you train a model to predict aleatoric uncertainty on this data set,
如果你训练一个模型来预测这个数据集上的偶然不确定性，
corners and boundaries have the highest aleatoric uncertainty,
角落和边界有最高的偶然不确定性，
because even if your pixels are like one row off or one column off,
因为即使你的像素像一行或一列分开，
that introduces noise into the model,
这也会向模型中引入噪音，
the model can still learn in the face of this noise,
在这种噪音面前，模型仍然可以学习，
but it does exist and it can't be reduced.
但它确实存在，不能减少。
So now that we know about data uncertainty or aleatoric uncertainty,
既然我们已经了解了数据不确定性或偶然不确定性，
let's move on to learning about epistemic uncertainty.
让我们继续学习认知不确定性。
As a recap, epistemic uncertainty can best be described as uncertainty in the model itself,
总而言之，认知不确定性可以最好地描述为模型本身的不确定性，
and it is reducible by adding data to the model.
并且可以通过在模型中添加数据来减少。
So with epistemic uncertainty,
因此，在认知不确定性的情况下，
essentially what we're trying to ask is,
本质上我们试图问的是，
is the model unconfident about a prediction.
这个模型对预测有信心吗。
So a really simple and very smart way to do this is,
一个非常简单和非常聪明的方法是，
let's say I train the same network multiple times with random initializations
假设我用随机初始化多次训练同一个网络，
and I ask it to predict the exact, I call it on the same input.
我要求它预测，我在相同输入调用它。
So let's say I give model 1 the exact same input,
假设我给模型 1 一个完全相同的输入，
and the blue X is the output of this model,
蓝色的 X 是这个模型的输出，
and then I do the same thing again with model 2,
然后我再用模型 2 做同样的事情，
and then again with model 3,
然后用模型 3 ，
and again with model 4,
然后在模型 4 ，
these models all have the exact same hyper parameters, the exact same architecture,
这些模型都具有完全相同的超参数，完全相同的体系结构，
and their train in the same way,
相同的训练方式，
the only difference between them is that,
它们之间的唯一区别是，
their weights are all randomly initialized,
它们的权重都是随机初始化的，
so where they start from is different.
因此它们从哪里开始是不同的。
And the reason why we can use this to determine epistemic uncertainty is,
我们之所以能用它来确定认知的不确定性，
because we would expect, that with familiar inputs in our network,
是因为我们预计，在我们的网络中有熟悉的输入时，
our networks should all converge to around the same answer,
我们的网络应该都收敛到相同的答案，
and we should see very little variance in the the log or the outputs that we're predicting.
我们应该会看到对数或我们预测的输出的很小的变化。
However, if a model has never seen a specific input before,
然而，如果一个模型以前从未见过特定的输入，
or that input is very hard to learn,
或者该输入很难学习，
all of these models should predict slightly different answers,
所有这些模型应该预测略有不同的答案，
and the variance of them should be higher than if they were predicting a similar input.
并且它们的方差应该高于它们预测类似输入的情况。
So creating an ensemble of networks is quite simple, quite simple,
因此，创建一个网络集合非常简单，
you start out with defining the num_ensembles you want,
你从定义你想要的 num_ensembles 开始，
you create them all the exact same way,
你以完全相同的方式创建它们，
and then you fit them all on the same training data and training data.
然后你把它们都放在相同的训练数据。
And then afterwards, when at inference time,
然后，当在推理时，
we call all of the models, every model in the ensemble on our specific input,
我们调用所有模型，集合中的每个模型，关于我们的特定输入，
and then we can treat our new prediction as the average of all of the ensembles,
然后我们可以将我们的新预测视为所有集合的平均值，
this results in a usually more robust and accurate prediction,
这通常会产生更稳健和更准确的预测，
and we can treat the uncertainty as the variance of all of these predictions,
我们可以将不确定性视为所有这些预测的方差，
again, remember that if we saw familiar inputs or inputs with low epistemic uncertainty,
记住，如果我们看到熟悉的输入或具有低认知不确定性的输入，
we should expect to have very little variance,
我们应该预期会有很小的方差，
and if we had a very unfamiliar input or something that was out of distribution
如果我们有一个非常不熟悉的输入，或者是分布之外的东西，
or something the model hasn't seen before,
或者是模型以前没有见过的东西，
we should have very high epistemic uncertainty or variance.
我们应该有非常高的认知不确定性或方差。
So what's the problem with this,
那么，这有什么问题，
can anyone raise their hand and tell me,
有没有人能举手告诉我，
what a problem with training an ensemble of networks is.
训练一组网络有什么问题。
So training an ensemble of networks is really compute expensive,
训练一组网络是计算成本高昂的，
even if your model is not very large,
即使你的模型不是很大，
training five copies of it or ten copies of it tends to, it takes up compute and time,
训练五个或十个副本往往会占用计算和时间，
and that's just not really feasible when we're training on specific tasks.
当我们在特定任务上进行训练时，这是不太可行的。
However, the key insight for ensembles is that,
然而，一组的关键洞察力是，
by introducing some method of randomness or stochasticity into our networks,
通过在我们的网络中引入某种随机性或随机性的方法，
we're able to estimate epistemic uncertainty,
我们能够估计认知的不确定性，
so another way that we've seen about introducing stochasticity into networks is by using dropout layers,
因此，我们已经看到的另一种将随机性引入网络的方法是使用 dropout 层，
we've seen dropout layers as a method of reducing overfitting,
我们把 dropout 层看作是一种减少过度拟合的方法，
because we randomly drop out different nodes in our, in our layer,
因为我们随机地丢弃了层中的不同节点，
and then we continue to propagate information through them
然后我们继续通过它们传播信息，
and it prevents models from memorizing data.
这阻止了模型记忆数据。
However, in the case of epistemic uncertainty,
然而，在认知不确定性的情况下，
we can add dropout layers after every single layer in our model,
我们可以在模型中的每一层之后添加 dropout 层，
and in addition, we can keep these dropout layers enabled at test time,
此外，我们可以在测试时保持这些 dropout 层处于启用状态，
usually we don't keep dropout layers enabled at test time,
通常，我们在测试时不会使 dropout 层处于启用状态，
because we don't want to lose any information about the the network's process or any weights when we're at inference time,
因为我们不想在推理时丢失有关网络进程或权重的任何信息，
however, when we're estimating epistemic uncertainty,
然而，当我们估计认知不确定性时，
we do want to keep dropout enabled at test time,
我们确实希望在测试时保持 dropout 启用，
because that's how we can introduce randomness, inference time as well.
因为这也是我们引入随机性和推理时间的方式。
So what we do here is we have one model,
所以我们在这里做的是我们有一个模型，
it's the same model the entire way through,
从头到尾都是一样的模型，
we add dropout layers with a specific probability,
我们以特定的概率添加 dropout 层，
and then we run multiple forward passes
然后我们运行多个前向传递，
and at every forward passes,
在每一次前向传递中，
different layers get different nodes in a layer get dropped out,
不同的层在一层中获得不同的节点被丢弃，
so we have that measure of randomness and stochasticity.
所以我们有随机性的度量。
So again, in order to implement this,
再说一次，为了实现这一点，
what we have is a model with the exact one model,
我们拥有的是一个完全相同的模型，
and then when we're running our forward passes,
然后当我们运行我们的向前传递时，
we can simply run T forward passes,
我们可以简单地运行 T 次向前传递，
where T is usually a number like twenty,
其中 T 通常是一个类似于 20 的数字，
we keep dropout enabled at test time,
我们在测试时保持 dropout 开启，
and then we use the mean of these samples as the new prediction
然后使用这些样本的平均值作为新的预测，
and the variance of these samples as a measure of epistemic uncertainty.
并使用这些样本的方差作为认知不确定性的衡量标准。
So both of the methods we talked about just now involves sampling,
所以我们刚才谈到的这两种方法都涉及到抽样，
and sampling is expensive,
而且抽样成本很高，
unsampling is very expensive,
反抽样成本非常高，
but even if you have a pretty large model,
但即使你有一个相当大的模型，
having or introducing dropout layers and calling twenty forward passes might also be something that's pretty infeasible,
引入 dropout 层和调用 20 个向前传递也可能是非常不可行的，
and at Themis, we're dedicated to developing innovative methods of estimating epistemic uncertainty,
在 Themis ，我们致力于开发评估认知不确定性的创新方法，
that don't rely on things like sampling,
这种方法不依赖于采样之类的东西，
so that they're more generalizable
因此它们更具普遍性，
and they're usable by more industries and people.
可以被更多的行业和人使用。
So, a method that we've developed to estimate,
因此，我们开发了一种方法来估计，
a method that we've studied to estimate epistemic uncertainty
我们研究过的估计认知不确定性的方法，
is by using generative modeling.
就是通过生成性建模。
So we've talked about VAE couple times now,
我们已经讨论过 VAE 几次了，
but let's say I trained VAE on the exact same data set, we were talking about earlier,
假设我用我们之前讨论过的完全相同的数据集训练了 VAE ，
which is only dogs and cats,
也就是说，只有狗和猫，
the latent space of this model would be comprised of features that relate to dogs and cats,
这个模型的潜在空间将由与狗和猫有关的特征组成，
and if I give it a prototypical dog,
如果我给它一个原型狗，
it should be able to generate a pretty good representation of this dog,
它应该能够产生一个很好的代表这只狗，
and it should have pretty low reconstruction loss.
它应该有相当低的重建损失。
Now, if I gave the same example of the horse to this VAE,
现在，如果我给这个 VAE 一个同样的马的例子，
the latent vector that this horse would be decoded to would be incomprehensible to the decoder of this network,
这匹马将被解码到的潜在向量对于这个网络的解码者来说是无法理解的，
the decoder wouldn't be able to know how to project the latent vector back into the original input space,
解码器将不知道如何将潜在向量投影回原始输入空间，
and therefore we should expect to see a much worse reconstruction here,
因此我们应该预期在这里会看到更糟糕的重建，
and we should see that the reconstruction loss is much higher
我们应该看到，重建损失更高，
than if we gave the model a familiar input or something that it was used to seeing.
比我们给模型一个熟悉的输入或它习惯看到的东西。
So now let's move on to
现在让我们来看看，
what I think is the most exciting method of estimating epistemic uncertainty,
我认为最令人兴奋的估计认知不确定性的方法，
that we'll talk about today.
我们今天要谈到的。
So in both of the examples before,
因此，在前面的两个例子中，
sampling is compute intensive,
采样是计算密集型的，
but generative modeling can also be compute intensive,
但生成式建模也可以是计算密集型的，
let's say you don't actually need a variational autoencoder for your task,
比如，你的任务实际上不需要变分自编码器，
then you're training an entire decoder for no reason
然后你无缘无故地训练整个解码器，
and other than to estimate the epistemic uncertainty,
除了估计认知不确定性，
so what if we had a method,
那么如果我们有一种方法，
that did not rely on generative modeling or sampling in order to estimate the epistemic uncertainty,
不依赖于生成性建模或采样来估计认知不确定性，
that's exactly what a method that we've developed here at Themis does.
这正是我们在 Themis 开发的方法所做的。
So we view learning as an evidence based process,
因此，我们认为学习是一个以证据为基础的过程，
so if you remember from earlier when we were training the ensemble
所以，如果你还记得之前我们训练全体，
and calling multiple ensembles on the same input,
我们在同一个输入上调用多个全体，
we received multiple predictions
我们收到了多个预测，
and we calculated that variance.
我们计算了那个方差。
Now, the way we frame evidential learning is
现在，我们框架证据学习的方式是，
what if we assume that those data points, those predictions,
如果我们假设这些数据点，那些预测，
were actually drawn from a distribution themselves,
实际上是从分布本身得出的，
if we could estimate the parameters of this higher order evidential distribution,
如果我们能够估计这种高阶证据分布的参数，
we would be able to learn this variance or this measure of epistemic uncertainty automatically
我们就能够自动学习这种方差或认知不确定性的这种测量，
without doing any sampling or generative modeling,
而不需要进行任何抽样或生成性建模，
and that's exactly what evidential uncertainty does.
而这正是证据不确定性所做的。
So now that we have many methods in our toolbox for estimating epistemic uncertainty,
现在我们的工具箱中有许多方法来估计认知不确定性，
let's go back to our real world example.
让我们回到现实世界中的例子。
Let's say again, the input is the same as before,
让我们再说一次，输入和以前一样，
it's an RGB image of some scene in a city,
它是城市中某个场景的 RGB 图像，
and the output again is a pixel level mask
输出也是像素级掩码，
of what every pixel in this image belongs to, which class it belongs to,
该图像中每个像素所属的类别，
which parts of the data set would you expect to have high epistemic uncertainty,
你预计数据集的哪些部分会有很高的认知不确定性，
in this example, take a look at the output of the model itself,
在本例中，我们来看看模型本身的输出，
the model does mostly well on semantic segmentation,
模型在语义切分方面做得很好，
however it gets the sidewalk wrong,
然而，它把人行道弄错了，
it assigns some of the sidewalk to the road,
它会将某些人行道指定给道路，
and other parts of the sidewalk are labeled incorrectly.
而其他部分的人行道标记不正确。
And we can, using epistemic uncertainty,
我们可以，利用认知的不确定性，
we can see why this is,
我们可以明白为什么会这样，
the areas of the sidewalk that are discolored have high levels of epistemic uncertainty,
变色的人行道区域具有高度的认知不确定性，
maybe this is because the model has never seen an example of a sidewalk with multiple different colors in it before,
这可能是因为该模型以前从未见过具有多种不同颜色的人行道的示例，
or maybe it hasn't been trained on examples with sidewalks generally,
或者可能它没有在具有人行道的示例上进行过训练，
either way,
无论哪种方式，
epistemic uncertainty has isolated this specific area of the image as an area of high uncertainty.
认知的不确定性将图像的这一特定区域隔离为高度不确定的区域。
So today, we've gone through two major challenges for robust deep learning,
今天，我们经历了实现稳健的深度学习两个主要挑战，
we've talked about bias,
我们已经谈到了偏差，
which is what happens when models are skewed by sensitive feature inputs
这是当模型被敏感的特征输入扭曲时发生的事情，
and uncertainty, which is when we can measure a level of confidence of a certain model.
以及不确定性，也就是我们可以衡量某个模型的置信度水平时发生的事情。
Now we'll talk about how Themis uses these concepts
现在，我们将讨论 Themis 如何使用这些概念
to build products that transform models
来构建转变模型的产品，
to make them more risk aware,
使它们更具风险意识，
and how we're changing the AI landscape in terms of safe and trustworthy AI.
以及我们如何在安全和值得信赖的人工智能方面改变人工智能的格局。
So at Themis,
因此，在 Themis 中，
we believe that uncertainty and bias mitigation
我们相信不确定性和偏见的缓解，
unlock a host of new solutions
开启了一系列解决方案，
to solving these problems with safe and responsible AI,
为了解决安全和负责任的人工智能的问题，
we can use bias and uncertainty to mitigate risk in every part of the AI life cycle.
我们可以使用偏见和不确定性来降低人工智能生命周期每个部分的风险。
Let's start with labeling data,
让我们从标记数据开始，
today, we talked about aleatoric uncertainty,
今天我们讨论了偶然不确定性，
which is a method to detect mislabeled samples,
这是一种检测错误标记的样本，
to highlight label noise,
突出标记噪音的方法，
and to generally maybe tell labelers to relabel images or samples that they've gotten,
通常可能会告诉标签员重新标记他们获得的图像或样本，
that may be wrong.
可能是错误的。
In the second part of this cycle,
在这个周期的第二部分中，
we have analyzing the data
我们已经分析了数据，
before a model is even trained on any data,
甚至在对任何数据进行模型训练之前，
we can analyze the bias that is present in this data set
我们可以分析这个数据集中存在的偏差，
and tell the creators whether or not they should add more samples,
告诉创建者他们是否应该添加更多的样本，
which demographics, which areas of the data set are underrepresented in the current data set
哪些人口统计数据，数据集中的哪些领域在当前数据集中没有得到充分代表，
before we even train a model on them.
甚至在我们对它们进行模型训练之前。
And then let's go to training the model,
然后让我们去训练这个模型，
once we're actually training a model,
一旦我们真正训练一个模型，
if it's already been trained on a biased data set,
如果它已经在有偏差的数据集上进行了训练，
we can debias it adaptively during training
我们可以在训练过程中自适应地 debias ，
using the methods that we talked about today.
使用我们今天讨论的方法。
And afterwards, we can also verify or certify deployed machine learning models,
然后，我们还可以验证或认证部署的机器学习模型，
making sure that models that are actually out there are as safe and unbiased as they claim they are,
确保实际存在的模型如它们声称的那样安全和公正，
and the way we can do this is
我们可以做到这一点的方法是，
by leveraging epistemic uncertainty or bias
通过利用认知的不确定性或偏差
in order to calculate the samples or data points that the model will do the worst on,
来计算模型在最差情况下会做的样本或数据点，
the model has the the most trouble learning or data set samples
模型上有有最困难的学习，最差的样本，
that are the most underrepresented in a model data set,
在模型数据集中最不能被代表的数据集样本，
if we can test the model on these samples,
如果我们可以在这些样本上测试模型，
specifically the hardest samples for the model,
特别是模型的最困难样本，
and it does well,
并且它做得很好，
then we know that the model has probably been trained in a fair and unbiased manner,
那么我们就知道模型可能已经以一种公平和公正的方式进行了训练，
that mitigates uncertainty.
以减少不确定性。
And lastly, we can think about,
最后，我们可以考虑一下，
we, we are developing a product at Themis called AI guardian,
我们正在 Themis 开发一款名为 AI Guardian 的产品，
and that's essentially a layer between the artificial intelligence algorithm and the user,
这本质上是人工智能算法和用户之间的一层，
and the way this works is,
它的工作原理是，
this is a type of algorithm,
这是一种算法，
that if you're driving an autonomous vehicle,
如果你驾驶一辆自动驾驶汽车，
would say, hey, the model doesn't actually know what is happening in the world around it right now,
会说，这个模型实际上并不知道它周围的世界现在发生了什么，
as the user, you should take control of this autonomous vehicle
作为使用者，你应该控制这辆自动驾驶汽车，
and we can apply this to areas outside autonomy as well.
我们也可以将这一点应用于自动驾驶之外的领域。
So you'll notice that I skipped one part of the cycle,
所以你会注意到我跳过了一个周期的一部分，
I skipped the part about building the model
我跳过了关于构建模型的部分，
and that's because today we're going to focus a little bit on famous AI's product called CAPSA,
这是因为今天我们将稍微关注一下新兴市场著名的人工智能产品 CAPSA ，
which is a model agnostic framework for risk estimation,
这是一个模型不可知的风险评估框架，
so CAPSA is an open source library,
所以 CAPSA 是一个开源库，
you all will actually use it in your lab today,
你们今天将在你们的实验室中使用它，
that transforms models,
它可以转换模型，
so that they're risk aware.
让它们意识到风险。
So this is a typical training pipeline,
因此，这是一个典型的训练管道，
you've seen this many times in the course, by now,
到目前为止，你们在课程中已经看过很多次，
we have our data, we have the model,
我们已经有了数据，我们有了模型，
and it's fed into the training algorithm
它被输入到训练算法中，
and we get a trained model at the end
最后我们得到了一个训练有素的模型，
that outputs a prediction for every input.
它为每一次输入输出一个预测。
But with CAPSA, what we can do is
但有了 CAPSA ，我们可以做的是，
by adding a single line into any training workflow,
通过在任何训练流程中添加一行，
we can turn this model into a risk aware variant,
我们可以将此模型转变为具有风险意识的变体，
that essentially calculates biases, uncertainty and label noise for you,
本质上为你计算偏差、不确定性和标签噪声，
because today as you've heard by now,
因为今天，正如你现在所听到的，
there are so many methods of estimating uncertainty and bias,
有如此多的方法来估计不确定性和偏差，
and sometimes certain methods are better than others,
有时某些方法比其他方法更好，
it's really hard to determine what kind of uncertainty you're trying to estimate
真的很难确定你试图估计的是哪种不确定性，
and how to do so,
以及如何估计，
so CAPSA takes care of this for you,
所以 CAPSA 会帮你处理这件事，
by inserting one line into your training workflow,
通过在你的训练流程中插入一行，
you can achieve a risk aware model,
你可以获得一个风险感知模型，
that you can then further analyze.
然后你可以进一步分析。
And so this is the one line that I've been talking about,
这就是我一直在谈论的一行，
after you build your model,
在构建模型之后，
you can just create a wrapper or you can call a wrapper,
你可以创建一个包装器，也可以调用一个包装器，
that CAPSA has an extensive library of,
CAPSA 拥有扩展库，
and then, in addition to achieving prediction, receiving predictions from your model,
然后，除了实现预测，从你的模型接收预测之外，
you can also receive whatever bias or uncertainty metric that you're trying to estimate.
你还可以得到你试图估计的任何偏差或不确定性指标。
And the way CAPSA works is,
CAPSA 的工作方式是，
it does this by wrapping models,
它通过包装模型实现这个，
for every uncertainty metric that we want to estimate,
对于我们想要估计的每个不确定性指标，
we can apply and create the minimal model modifications as necessary,
我们可以根据需要应用和创建最小的模型修改，
while preserving the initial architecture and predictive capabilities,
同时保留初始架构和预测能力，
in the case of aleatoric uncertainty,
在偶然不确定性的情况下，
this could be adding a new layer,
这可能会增加一层新的东西，
in the case of a variational autoencoder,
在变分自编码器的情况下，
this could be creating and training the decoder
这可能是创建和训练解码器，
and calculating the reconstruction loss on the fly.
并在运行中计算重建损失。
And this is an example of CAPSA
这是一个 CAPSA 的例子，
working on one of the data sets that we talked about today,
处理我们今天讨论的其中一个数据集，
which was the cubic data set with added noise in it,
那就是增加了噪声的立方数据集，
and also another simple classification task,
还有另一项简单的分类任务，
and the reason why I wanted to show this image
我之所以想展示这张图片，
is to show that using CAPSA,
是为了展示使用 CAPSA ，
we can achieve all of these uncertainty estimates
我们可以实现所有这些不确定性估计，
with very little additional added work.
在几乎不增加额外工作的情况下。
So using all of the products that I just talked about today and using CAPSA,
所以，使用我今天刚刚谈到的所有产品，使用 CAPSA ，
Themis is unlocking the key to deploy deep learning models safely across fields,
Themis 解锁了跨领域安全部署深度学习模型的关键，
we can now answer a lot of the questions that the headlines were raising earlier,
我们现在可以回答早些时候头条新闻提出的许多问题，
which is when should a human take control of an autonomous vehicle,
即人类应该在什么时候控制自动驾驶汽车，
what types of data are underrepresented in commercial autonomous driving pipelines,
在商业自动驾驶管道中，哪些类型的数据代表不足，
we now have educated answers to these questions
我们现在已经对这些问题有了有根据的答案，
due to products that Themis is developing.
由于 Themis 正在开发的产品。
And in spheres such as medicine and health care,
在医学和医疗保健等领域，
we can now answer questions such as,
我们现在可以回答这样的问题，
when is a model uncertain about a life threatening diagnosis,
一个模型什么时候对危及生命的诊断是不确定的，
When should this diagnosis be passed to a medical professional
应在什么时候将此诊断传递给医学专业人员，
before this information is conveyed to a patient,
在将此信息传达给患者之前，
or what types of patients might drug discovery algorithms be biased against.
或者药物发现算法可能对哪类患者有偏见。
And today, the, the application that you guys will focus on is on facial detection,
今天，你们将关注的应用程序是面部检测，
you'll use CAPSA in today's lab
你将在今天的实验室中使用 CAPSA ，
to thoroughly analyze a common facial detection data set,
来彻底分析常见面部检测数据集，
that we've perturbed in some ways for you,
我们以某些方式扰乱的，
so that you can discover them on your own,
以便你可以自己发现它们，
and we we highly encourage you to compete in the competition,
我们强烈鼓励你参加比赛，
which the details are described in the lab,
比赛的细节在实验室中描述，
but basically it's about analyzing this data set,
但从根本上讲，它是关于分析这些数据集，
creating risk aware models,
创建风险意识模型，
that mitigate bias and uncertainty in the specific training pipeline.
以减少特定训练管道中的偏见和不确定性。
And so at Themis our goal is,
所以，在 Themis ，我们的目标是，
to design, advance, and deploy trustworthy AI across industries and around the world,
在各个行业和世界各地设计、推进和部署值得信赖的人工智能，
we're passionate about scientific innovation,
我们热衷于科学创新，
we release open source tools like the ones you'll use today,
我们发布了像你们今天将使用的开源工具，
and our products transform AI workflows and make artificial intelligence safer for everyone,
我们的产品改变了人工智能工作流程，使人工智能对每个人都更安全，
we partner with industries around the globe
我们与全球各地的行业合作，
and we're hiring for the upcoming summer and for full time roles,
我们正在为即将到来的夏季和全职职位招聘，
so if you're interested,
因此，如果你感兴趣，
please send an email to careers@themisai.io
请发一封电子邮件到 careers@themisai.io ，
or apply by submitting your resume to the deep learning resume drop
或者通过向深度学习简历投递来申请，
and we'll see those resumes and get back to you.
我们会看到这些简历并回复你。
Thank you.
谢谢。